Okay. So now we have the wireframes implemented for both screens.
But what does it look like on the tablet? Well, unfortunately,
when we take the phone UI and stretch it out on
a tablet, it doesn't look that great. There's a lot of empty
white space here. We could better take advantage of this screen
real estate by showing more useful information. For example, why do the
details need to be a tap away when they could just
as easily fit on this screen? And, furthermore, if the user wants
to look through the full list of forecasts, their eyes
must go like this, which is an unpleasant reading experience. If
we want the user to read some content, we should keep
the width narrower, so that they can scan it quickly. These
considerations are part of responsive
design. Responsive design means designing your
app by keeping in mind that it'll be used across a
range of different device screen sizes. But how do we do
that, and what does it mean to build for larger screen
devices like tablets. Well, I can show you some examples of
how apps adapt using multi-pane layouts. In the Android Design Guide,
there's a section on multi-pane layouts. One technique is to combine
multiple views together. For example, in the People app, you have
the contact list and the contact card for additional details. On
the tablet, we can put them side by side. This is
also known as the master detail flow. This is the master
list and this is the detail pane. In the settings app,
we have another example. The column width adjust based on the
available screen width. In the calendar app, we have panels, and
they stack vertically in the portrait orientation but horizontally in the
landscape orientation. There also a couple of other examples that you
can look through as well. If you want more information on
designing for tablets or responsive design in general, you can check
out the links below for more details. In this course, we're
learning how to build up the phone UI first, and then the
tablet UI. But in reality, when we're designing
it, we thought about responsive design from day
one. When you're building your own app, it's
bad practice to just completely design and build
your phone app and then start to brainstorm
about the tablet UI. That's because the tablet
UI often has an impact on the phone
design, as well as the architectural decisions made here.